Joel T. Rummel

925 S State St, Ann Arbor, MI 48107 phone: 269-944-9381

email: joelrummel@yahoo.com portfolio: joelrummel.net

I'm a college junior studying Computer Science with three years of internship experience in software development, looking for an opportunity to broaden my experience as a computer scientist. From web apps to video games to robotics, I've been passionate about writing all sorts of code since middle school, and I am comfortable in a wide variety of programming environments.

Check out my portfolio at joelrummel.net!

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI | September 2018

- Studying Computer Science at the College of Literature, Science, and the Arts
- Currently a junior, expected graduation: May 2022
- Current cumulative GPA: 3.03

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Intern, Spencer Manufacturing, South Haven, MI | June 2020—Current

- Designed and developed a custom React Native project management app for Android, iOS, and web browsers
 - o Capable of account management, timekeeping, issue tracking, group instant messaging, and more
 - o Backend written in PHP with a MySQL database
 - o Currently being internally distributed to replace company's existing timekeeping and group chat solutions

Quality Software Development Intern, Whirlpool Corporation, Benton Harbor, MI | June 2018—August 2019

- Worked full-time during the summers of 2018 and 2019, and part-time remotely during the Winter 2019 term
- Designed and developed a web application in Google Apps Script for a sub-team in India to help process large amounts of claims data on company products
- Led the development of multiple additional quality data analysis programs and web applications for internal use
 - These programs continue to see use today by hundreds of company engineers and quality analysts

ACTIVITIES & EXTRACURRICULARS

Michigan Engineering Zone Mentor, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI | Fall 2018—Fall 2019

- Served as a mentor for the U-M student organization Michigan Engineering Zone, a group that mentors Detroit high school robotics teams
 - Helped teach high school students how to wire and program FIRST Robotics Competition robots

High School FRC Robotics Team Member, South Haven High School, South Haven, MI | December 2013—May 2018

- Served as leader of the Programming/Electronics sub-team and wrote autonomous programs for team robots
- Designed and developed team website
- Frequently performed community outreach activities, such as presentations for businesses/organizations
- Developed scouting software to help the team summarize large amounts of data about other robots through an online API
- Served as an "Alliance Captain" (leader and representative of 4 different schools/teams) at 2018 World Championship

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Fluent in the following languages/technologies:

- Java
- C++
- Python
- HTML/CSS
- PHP
- JavaScript
- React.js
- React Native/Expo
- SQL

OTHER SKILLS

Proficient with the following tools:

- Git and GitHub
- Windows, MacOS, and Linux environments
- Command-line environments for any OS
- Database Management Systems such as MySQL
- Google Apps Script
- Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint
- Game development engines such as Godot